e-onsoftware.com 2019-07-26

# Privacy Statement

### _Learn about Bentley’s commitment to your privacy protection._

**Last Updated:   April 3, 2019**

Your privacy is important to Bentley. This Bentley Privacy Statement (" **Privacy Statement** ") tells you about how we collect, use, disclose, transfer, and store your information, as well as the choices you have regarding your information.  It also gives you information about our marketing and advertising practices and offline activities.

## GENERAL INFORMATION

Bentley’s Privacy Statement applies to information that you provide to Bentley or which is derived from the information collected as described in this Privacy Statement.  It also includes any Information derived from your use of Bentley.com and other Bentley websites and applications that include a link or reference to this Privacy Statement, as well as information about you collected offline.  The use of cookies, and any information that is gathered by them or other web tracking technologies, is subject to the disclosures and options provided in our [Cookie Statement](https://www.bentley.com/en/cookie-policy).

## EUROPEAN UNION GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION

If you reside in the EU, your relationship is with Bentley Systems International Limited, and the data protection regulations of the EU apply.

Bentley will process personal data, as provided in this Privacy Statement, for Bentley’s legitimate interests, or as necessary to enter into or perform a contract with you, or as required by EU law.  Where your consent is required, we will obtain your permission before sending you marketing and promotional material about Bentley as required by law and regulation.  You may withdraw your consent at any time.  Learn more about Your Choices and Controls. 

We transfer your personal data to the US and other countries, which may be outside the country in which you live.  We use European Commission-approved contract clauses and Privacy Shield certification to help protect your personal data.

Learn more information about Bentley’s GDPR Compliance Program and Subscription Entitlement Service for EU Accounts.

## LEARN MORE

Our primary goal is to provide you with information about:

## Information We Receive and Collect

## How We Use the Information We Collect

## Reasons We Share the Information We Collect

## Your Choices and Controls

## EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (EU RESIDENTS)

## Cookies and Similar Technologies

## Other Important Privacy Information

## Information We Receive and Collect

Bentley collects, uses, and transfers information from and about you to provide with the best experiences with our products and services; to improve and secure our products and services; to respond to your inquiries and contact you regarding our products and services; to manage your relationship with us; to best serve your interests by customizing your experience and interactions with Bentley; and for the other purposes described in this Privacy Statement. The type of information Bentley may collect from or about you includes:

**Name and Contact Information**

| 

Information including your name, email address, postal address, phone number, and similar contact information when you create a user ID to access our websites or applications, create a user profile, register for an event or other offering, make a purchase, or contact us for services, support or other reasons.  
  
---|---  
  
**Event Registration**

| 

Information required to sign-up or register for an event, webinar, or other Bentley event. This may include your name, email address, username and password. Event registration and attendance is subject to [Bentley’s Event Registrant Terms and Conditions](https://prod-bentleycdn.azureedge.net/-/media/files/documents/miscellaneous/general_event_terms_and_conditions.pdf?la=en&modified=20180705203636&hash=3C6F33002EFF04B6082AAD165CA8A8B2E6413958).   
  
**Login and Authentication Credentials**

| 

Username, passwords, PIN when you use your telephone number to log-in, security and authentication credentials including security questions and answers, and any unique ID number used to identify you and your associated information.  
  
**Demographic Information**

| 

Demographic information, such as your ZIP code, country, preferences, interests, and other similar things.  
  
**Purchase and Transaction Information**

| 

Information associated with your purchases, such as your contact information and including billing address. We use a third-party payment processor and do not receive credit card or other financial information. You may contact our payment processor [Cybersource](https://www.cybersource.com/ "Cybersource") with any questions regarding its use of your information.  
  
**Websites, Servers, Browsers Data**

| 

Information collected automatically when you communicate with us, access our websites and servers through a browser, application, or other client. This information  includes data about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click, and other actions taken in connection with our websites and services. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times, and referring website addresses. When you receive newsletters or promotional email from Bentley, we may use Web beacons (described here), customized links, or similar technologies to determine that the email has been opened and which links you click to provide you more focused email communications or other information in the future.  
  
**Usage Data**

| 

We require you to log in when you activate and use our software and products, including our cloud services. We monitor and collect certain usage information. For example, we track your device, products, and features, and other usage data, such as the date and time the application was used. You can get more information by reading the terms of service or software license agreement that applies to the products and applications you are using.  
  
**Channel Partners**

| 

We receive and collect your information if you make a purchase through our channel partners or ecommerce providers.  
  
**Data Supplementation**

| 

To keep our databases accurate and current, we may combine information you give us with information from public sources and trustworthy companies. For example, we may use services from other companies to ensure that we have accurate contact information and to tell us your geographic area based on your IP address, allowing us to provide you with more relevant content and offerings.  
  
**Contacting Us**

| 

When you contact us to request services, support, or other information, we may keep a record of the communication and your contact information.  
  
**Location Information**

| 

We collect data about your location when you enable location-based services or features, such as location derived from your IP address or data.  
  
**Social Networking Pages**

| 

We have our own pages on many social networking sites, such as Facebook and LinkedIn. We collect information when you visit and interact with our social networking pages. Be sure to review the privacy and data usage policies of any social networking platform you use to learn more about its privacy practices.  
  
Bentley stores the information that we collect from and about you in the United States, regardless of where you reside or where the information originates. This information is accessed by Bentley affiliates, employees, contractors, and service providers located throughout the world, only as necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Statement. If you are in the European Union, Switzerland, or another region with laws governing data collection, transfer, and use, you agree to the transfer to, and processing and use of, your information in the United States and other countries where privacy laws may be considered less strict than those laws of your jurisdiction. 

If you are a resident of the European Union, please see the **EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework** section below.

## How We Use the Information We Collect

Bentley uses the information that we collect from and about you in the following ways to conduct our business and pursue our legitimate interests,  including: 

**Providing, improving, and personalizing services** | 

  * Deliver the services or carry out the transactions you have requested
  * Provide you with the Bentley websites and applications for which you have registered, as well as any other products, services, support, or information you have requested
  * Provide customer support and service
  * Perform research and analysis aimed at improving our products, services, and technologies
  * Get a better understanding of how our websites and applications are being used so we can improve them
  * Diagnose problems in our websites and applications 

---|---  
  
**Communication**

| 

  * Send you business communications, including welcome letters, billing reminders, technical service issues information, expiration reminders, and security announcements
  * Send product surveys or promotional mailings to inform you of other products or services available from Bentley and affiliates
  * Update you on service requests or new services and benefits 

**Marketing and Advertising**

| 

  * Tailor a website, application, or Bentley marketing content to your likely interests and preferences
  * Send information about Bentley, new application releases, special offers, and similar information
  * Conduct market research about our customers, their interests, and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns 

**Other Legitimate Purposes**

| 

  * Invite you to participate in surveys regarding our products or services
  * Furnish and maintain our online environments
  * Secure our networks and online environments
  * Investigate or prevent an actual or suspected crime or injury to Bentley or others 
  * As required by law or in response to a request from law enforcement authorities or other government officials (including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements) 

**You may manage your preferences or unsubscribe to marketing and advertising communications at any time bycontacting us.**

Bentley may anonymize personal data provided under this Privacy Statement to create anonymized data sets, which will be used to improve Bentley and its affiliates’ product and service offerings. 

If we have an existing business relationship with you, Bentley may inform you, where permitted by law, about its products, services, and events that are similar or relate to our business relationship. 

## Reasons We Share the Information We Collect

We do not sell or otherwise disclose information that we collect to others, except as described in this Privacy Statement. Bentley may share your information that we collect with our controlled subsidiaries and affiliates. 

In some cases, Bentley may share information with vendors or companies that help us run our business by processing information on behalf of Bentley.  This shared information would be for the purposes of data processing or hosting or storage, delivering customer support, processing credit card payments, social media and marketing, event support, and sending emails on our behalf. In such cases, these companies will be permitted to obtain only the information that they need to deliver the respective services and are not allowed to use your information for any other purpose, except where required by law. Such vendors and agents must abide by our data privacy and security requirements, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information, except where required by law to disclose your information. Bentley may also share information with carefully selected strategic partners who provide services and sponsor events that may be of interest to you. These companies are obligated to protect your information and use it in accordance with their own privacy policies and practices.

Some Bentley web pages allow you to choose to share your information with select Bentley partners so that they can contact you about their products, services, or offers. Other sites do not share your contact information with third parties for marketing purposes, but instead may give you a choice as to whether you wish to receive communications from Bentley on behalf of external business partners about a partner’s particular offering (without transferring your information to the third party).

Some Bentley services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such services, both Bentley and the other company may receive information collected in connection with the co-branded services. The other company's use of your information is subject to such other company's own privacy policies and practices, and Bentley is not responsible for the privacy practices of, or use of your information by, such other companies.

We may share your personal information with trusted participants in our sales and marketing chain, including, but not limited to, authorized resellers, distributors, and business partners ("Channel Partners") for the limited purposes of selling, marketing, or providing support for certain product and service offerings. When these Channel Partners transfer information to us, we treat that information as described in this Privacy Statement. We take measures to help ensure that our Channel Partners protect the confidentiality, integrity, and security of any personal information we share with them. 

We may access and/or disclose information we collect if we believe that such action is necessary to: (a) comply with the law or legal process served on Bentley; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Bentley (including the enforcement of our agreements) or third parties; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Bentley services or members of the public. If we merge with another company or reorganize some part or all of our business, assets, or stock (including if we file for bankruptcy or similar proceeding), we may share information we collect from and about you in connection with the merger or reorganization. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that any acquirer may continue to use information that we collect from and about you as set forth in this Privacy Statement.

## Your Choices and Controls

You may have the ability to view or edit information we collect from and about you online. The appropriate method(s) for accessing your information will depend on which sites or services you have used. Some Bentley webpages or services may collect information that you may be able to access through alternative means of access described by the service. Or you can use our contact us form and we will contact you regarding your request.

You can stop the delivery of future marketing and promotional email from Bentley and services by following the specific instructions in the email. You may also have the option of proactively making choices about the communications you receive from Bentley by contacting us. However, we may send out emails periodically,  informing you of administrative and technical service issues about the products and services that you are using. These communications are considered essential to the provision of the service that you have requested. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered a part of the service you have chosen. 

You can also click here about the types of cookies and similar technologies we use, why we use them, and how you can exercise your choices.

## **EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework (EU RESIDENTS)**

Bentley Systems, Incorporated complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union to the United States. Bentley has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of _Notice_ , _Choice_ , _Accountability for Onward Transfer_ , _Security_ , _Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation_ , _Access_ , and _Recourse, Enforcement and Liability_ , and the 16 Supplemental Principles (collectively, " **Privacy Shield Principles** "). Such adherence is subject to investigation and enforcement by the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. 

Bentley's participation in the Privacy Shield applies to all personal information that is subject to this Privacy Statement and is received by or on behalf of Bentley from the European Union and European Economic Area. Bentley will comply with the Privacy Shield Principles in respect of such personal information. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Statement and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern in respect of such personal information. Bentley’s adherence to the Privacy Shield Principles may be limited to the extent necessary to meet national security, public interest, or law enforcement requirements.

Bentley’s accountability for personal information that it receives under the Privacy Shield framework and subsequently transfers to a third party is described in the Privacy Shield Principles. In particular, Bentley remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles, if third-party agents that we engage to process personal information on our behalf do so in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, unless we prove that we are not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

You have the right to access your personal information maintained by Bentley under the Privacy Shield framework, and to correct, amend, or delete such information where it is inaccurate or processed unlawfully, as described in the Privacy Shield Principles. To exercise these rights, please contact us by clicking on this contact us link.

You have the right to lodge a complaint with an applicable data protection authority. If you reside in Europe, you have the right to lodge a compliant in the European country of your habitual residence, place of work, or place of an alleged infringement, if you consider that the processing of your personal data infringes applicable EU data protection laws. A list of all European supervisory authorities and their respective contact information is available [here](https://urldefense.proofpoint.com/v2/url?u=http-3A__ec.europa.eu_justice_article-2D29_structure_data-2Dprotection-2Dauthorities_index-5Fen.htm&d=DwMGaQ&c=hmGTLOph1qd_VnCqj81HzEWkDaxmYdIWRBdoFggzhj8&r=VmMd4KRmdyfXTTetC21WFeGPy6JRr2GPVevN2LBt24Q&m=jzR9N5EHe5n8upTa63BR1dCogTiN_B7DIJaXs34rN-c&s=G8dxVY6ZbAhKn-MgHpuMjyX9kdDfKOuudaTYzbPVnh0&e=). 

In addition, Bentley provides individuals with certain choices regarding how we use and disclose personal information we receive under the Privacy Shield framework. First, if Bentley uses your personal information for a materially different purpose than what it was originally collected, or discloses your personal information to a third party (other than third party providers acting on our behalf), we will first provide you with a clear, conspicuous, and readily available mechanism to opt-out of any such use or disclosure (for example, by sending you an email seeking your consent). All of our email communications include the ability to opt-out from receiving future emails, except those emails that are necessary to provide you with the services you have requested or purchased. If you have any questions about your choices regarding how we use and disclose your personal information, or how to exercise these choices, please contact us via our contact us form.

We encourage you to contact us if you have a Privacy Shield-related (or general privacy-related) complaint or inquiry by clicking on this contact us link. For any complaints that cannot be resolved with Bentley directly, Bentley has chosen to cooperate with the American Arbitration Association, an alternative dispute resolution provider, to resolve such complaints at no charge to you. Please visit <http://go.adr.org/privacyshield.html> for more information and to file a complaint. As further explained in the Privacy Shield Principles, a binding arbitration option will also be made available to you to address residual complaints not resolved by any other means.

To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, please visit [www.privacyshield.gov](http://www.privacyshield.gov/ "www.privacyshield.gov"). To view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt00000004EOGAA2>.

## Other Important Privacy Information

**Security of Your Information**  
Bentley is committed to protecting the security of information we collect from and about you. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect this information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number or password) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as Transport Layer Security. If a password is used to help protect your accounts and information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone, you should always choose to log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

**Collection and Use of Children’s Information**  
Bentley webpages and services are intended for general audiences and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. When a Bentley webpage does collect age information, and users identify themselves as under 13, the site will either block such users from providing personal information, or will seek to obtain consent from parents for the collection, use, and sharing of their children’s personal information. We will not knowingly ask children under the age of 13 to provide personal information to us. Bentley strongly encourages you to talk with your children about communicating with strangers and disclosing personal information online and about using the Internet safely.

**Use of Cookies**  
We and our approved partners use cookies and similar technologies on our websites, services, applications, tools, and electronic communications (collectively referred to as our “ **sites and services** ”) that automatically receive and track certain data about your device and interaction with our sites and services. You can read more here about the types of cookies and similar technologies we use, why we use them, and how you can exercise your choices.

**Use of Third-Party Ad Networks**  
The majority of the online banner advertisements that you see on Bentley web pages are displayed by Bentley. However, we allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to display advertisements on Bentley web pages. Some of these ad networks may place a persistent cookie on your computer to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement. In this way, ad networks may compile information about where you, or others who are using your computer, saw their advertisements and determine which ads are clicked. This information allows an ad network to deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. Bentley does not have access to nor does it control the cookies that may be placed on your computer by the third-party ad servers or ad networks. You can read more here about the types of cookies and similar technologies we use, why we use them, and how you can exercise your choices.

Bentley maintains relationships with a number of third-party ad networks currently operating. Those ad networks that use persistent cookies may offer you a way to opt out of ad targeting. You may find more information at the website of either the individual ad network or the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/ "Network Advertising Initiativ").

**Links to Other Sites**  
Bentley webpages may contain links to other sites. Bentley is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other websites. Please refer to the policies of the respective site.

**Enforcement of This Privacy Statement**  
If you have questions regarding this Privacy Statement, you should contact us by clicking on this contact us link.

**Changes to This Privacy Statement**  
We will update this Privacy Statement when necessary to reflect customer feedback and changes in our services and practices. When we make changes, we will post the " **Last Revised** " date at the top of this Privacy Statement so you know when those changes were made. If there are material changes to this Privacy Statement or in how Bentley will use information we collect from and about you, we will notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes prior to implementing the change or by directly sending you a notification. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to be informed of how Bentley is protecting your information.

**Contacting Us**  
Bentley welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Statement. If you have questions about this Privacy Statement, or believe that we have not adhered to it, please contact us by clicking on this contact us link.
